GUSTAVO MARIN

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Location: Madrid, Spain Email: gustavoandresmarin@gmail.com



Online version

HIGHLIGHTS

- 15+ years of experience in the software industry.
- Experience with full software development lifecycle experience and DevOps culture.
- Strong experience in backend/frontend with various architecture layouts.
- Strong analytical, debugging, and troubleshooting skills.
- Great team player, good leader and mentor for other team members.

ABOUT ME

As a Senior Software Engineer with over 15 years of experience, I have worked with a broad range of technologies and architectures, from simple web apps to cloud native apps making use of multiple programming languages and frameworks. I possess strong leadership and communication abilities.

I prioritise delivering quality software on time and smoothly guiding teams through all stages of the project lifecycle. The technical skills I apply at work, enable me to contribute directly to the project's success as well as skilfully mentor team members towards their development.

I am a problem-solver committed to continuous learning to keep delivering innovative solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

| Golang | Expert |
|------------------|----------|
| JS, TS & Node.JS | Expert |
| Python | Moderate |

DATABASES, MESSAGING & TOOLS

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Oracle

MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Cassandra

NATS Streaming, RabbitMQ, ZeroMQ, Kafka

GraphQL, Influx, Grafana

DEVOPS AND INFRA

Kubernetes, Helm, Operators, AWS

Docker, Docker-compose

GitOps, Gitlab CI, Github Actions

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - Product Engineer

Jun 2023 - Present

Monzo UK

At Monzo UK, I worked in the Growth collective across the Customer Acquisition and CRM Messaging squads. In Customer Acquisition, I developed systems for tracking ad conversions with partners like Google, Meta, Adjust, and TikTok, and integrated a value-based bidding model to optimize ROI. In CRM Messaging, I built a system for personalized daily messaging to over 10 million users, combining business rules with a machine learning model to select the best messages based on user attributes. Additionally, I implemented Statsig experimentation to enable data-driven decision-making and optimize messaging strategies.

- **Tech Stack**:Golang, TypeScript, GraphQL, Cassandra, Kafka, BigQuery.
- Tools:Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Terraform, CI/CD, GitHub Actions, Sentry, Contentful, Statsig, CACI.

Technical Lead | Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2022 - Jun 2023

ThoughtWorks

Personio DE: In this Payroll software provider company I'm responsible for implementing complex proration rules in the payroll domain. Developing the related microservices in Kotlin and migrating functionality from a large PHP monolith.

Motability UK: Worked as a DevOps Engineer at an UK-based charity offering mobility solutions to disabled individuals, I developed software solutions to upgrade and migrate their cloud platform. I focused on enhancing system maintainability and worked closely with the development team to implement continuous integration and deployment best practices while streamlining the release process.

- Tech Stack: Golang, Node.JS, Bash, Kotlin.
- Tools: OpenShift, ArgoCD, Jenkins, Groovy, GitlabCI, Split.IO, Datadog, 1Password.

Technical Lead | Senior Software Engineer

2018 - 2022

Konstellation.io

Open-source software to build, deploy and evolve AI solutions at any scale. Worked as one of the first engineers in the team, helping to shape the vision of a viable MVP software. I built the architecture and its components, and worked on their final implementation. This complex project was unique as it bridged the work of science teams, engineers and DevOps teams.

MetTel: various projects related to process automation that involved AI/ML models.

Celgene: Engineering and MLOps, helping the science team to take the code AI/ML models to production.

- Tech Stack: Golang, Node.JS, Python, REST, gRPC, GraphQL, MongoDB, NATS streaming.
- Tooling: Kubernetes, MLOps, GitOps, CI/CD, Machine Learning.

Technical Lead | Senior Software Engineer

2014 - 2022

Intelygenz

Joined this service company as Technical Lead to facilitate switch to backend Node.JS. I participated in key projects in a range of activities: technical decisions, software architecture and good practice quality tests and code reviews.

X by Orange: designing and implementing the microservice architecture interconnected with an event driven system based on Apache Kafka to communicate the different domains of this large and ambitious project. Championing E2E processes and DevOps culture implementation.

Azlo: I joined this startup-like project for the BBVA USA incubator after the first MVP had been done. I helped in refactoring the code and architecture. Integrating several 3rd party services, interacting with KVM storages, syncing data with BBVA APIs.

Telepizza: I worked on creating a hybrid Ionic app for food order and delivery. A challenging project aimed to optimize the app for targeting Android, iOS, phones and tablets, and to integrate several third party APIs as well as E2E testing strategy.

- Tech stack: Golang, Node.JS, GraphQL, MongoDB, NATS streaming, Ionic, Angular, TDD, E2E.
- Tooling: Kubernetes, Docker, API First, Cloud Native, Openshift, MLOps, CI/CD, Machine Learning, Kafka...

Senior Software Engineer

2007 - 2014

PRISA DIGITAL

Spain's leading company in production of digital news and information. Working with their proprietary framework, both Javascript and PHP.

- 2009: Technical Lead to redesign and refactor cuatro.com, leading a group of developers.
- 2011: designer and developer of VOD platform's security layer for Canal+ video on demand feeds.
- **2012**: new Push Notification project with innovative technologies as Amazon WS, RabbitMQ and cloud cluster management.
- 2013: developing Canal+ Web Live Streaming and VOD platform.
- Tech Stack: JavaScript, jQuery, ExtJS, XML, MySQL, PHP, Pear, Zend, shell scripting

Software Engineer 2002 - 2006

FIAT AUTO ESPAÑA

International automotive group. Participated in FIAT's Link intranet in all phases of development from analysis through design, coding, testing, and implementation in Spain as well as migrating the rest of European markets.

Design and development for retail and workshops application to control and benchmark car repair processes and automation services to update stock data.

Tech Stack: PHP, Oracle, PL/SQL, XML, Soap, JavaScript, HTML

Developer | SysAdmin

1999 - 2002

- **Claxson Interactive**: Multimedia company, entertainment content provider worldwide. Senior PHP developer involved in code migration from ASP to PHP and from MySQL to Oracle and PL/SQL. Also involved in backend for content administration and a multilingual/multiplatform forum application.
- **Powersite Argentina**: Websites development company. A programmer for several customer websites, doing coding tasks, SQL procedures, and proprietary framework development in PHP.
- **Zarcrom Argentina**: Web hosting company. A server administrator and technical support to customers, performing administration tasks of Apache on Cobalt RAQ servers, new sites configuration, user and sites management, DNS configuration. Also, a webmaster for several customers and the company's main site in Argentina.
 - Tech stack: HTML, PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, PL/SQL, Apache, Linux, shell scripting

EDUCATION

| Ingeniería en Sistemas de Información at Universidad Tecnológica Nacional | 1995 - 1999 |
|---|-------------|
| Bachiller Técnico at Instituto Politécnico Superior | 1990 - 1994 |
| COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION | |
| GNU/Linux LPIC-1 Certification at Instituto Novatech Madrid | 2006 |
| English technical translation at Instituto Politécnico Superior | 1994 |

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- I love Tabletop RPG games, and I try lots of indie games and some good old D&D.
- Reading fantasy and/or science fiction.
- Woodworking, in contrast with all the "virtual" work, I like to relax giving new purpose to old wood.